# **GOKUL NARAYANAN SATHYA NARAYANAN**

### Summary

Robot software engineer with 3 years of experience in building robots and deploying it in real-world. Have diverse skill set in developing algorithms for various robot stacks, with primary focus on planning and reinforcement learning stack.

## **Work History**

Current

2019-08

2018-05

# 2019-08 - Advanced Robotics Intern

SIEMENS, Berkeley, CA

- Performance comparison of motion planning algorithms (sampling based vs search based vs optimization based).
- Designing and developing a modular automation solution to stitch garments using collaborative robot (UR3) which will increase the production rate by 20%. Skill: Python, ROS, MATLAB
- Developed motion primitives and waypoint trajectory generator for the collaborative robot to perform different kinds of stitches

# 2018-10 - Research Assistant

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

- Developed a planning framework to perform precise in-hand manipulation of objects with <1 mm accuracy. Skill: Python, ROS</li>
- Developed a symbolic task planner integrated with a hierarchical reinforcement learning framework to perform loco-manipulation task.

# 2016-05 - Robot Software Engineer

ASIMOV Robotics, Cochin, Kerala

- Directed 3 software developers in building the software stack of an autonomous mobile robot. Skill: Python, ROS, C++.
- Achieved 94% success rate in long range navigation tasks by introducing recovery behaviors in the state machine of the robot.
- Developed path planning algorithms (Variants of A\*) for the mobile robot to avoid obstacles and navigate autonomously.
- Reduced the error in localization module by fusing the sensory data such as odometry, LIDAR and IMU using Extended Kalman Filter.
- Spearheaded the research group in building 'Cranio-facial Surgical Robot' in collaboration with Biotechnology Research Institute.

# Accomplishments

- Built India's first general purpose mobile robot assistant which can autonomously navigate hospitals to deliver medications to patients.
- Secured 30K funding for the startup from government by writing technical proposals.

#### Contact

Address

Berkeley, CA, 94704

Phone

1-5087235730

E-mail

gsathyanarayanan@wpi.edu

**Portfolio** 

https://gokul-gokz.github.io

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/gokulnarayanan

### **Skills**

Data structures and Algorithms

Motion Planning

Reinforcement Learning

Task planning

Mobile Robots

Manipulators

### **Software**

C++



Python



Robot operating System



**MATLAB** 



Pytorch



### **Education**

2018-08 -Masters: Robotics and Automation Engineering Current

Worcester Polytechnic Institute - Worcester, MA

2012-08 -**Bachelor: Robotics and Automation Engineering** 

PSG College of Technology - Coimbatore

### **Projects**

2016-05

- Within Hand manipulation of objects using deep reinforcement learning techniques.
- Performance comparison of trajectory tracking controllers for UR5 manipulator.
- Extended Kalman Filter based localization for mobile robots.
- Teleoperation of ATLAS robot arm using Razer hydra controller.

### **Papers**

- Within Hand Manipulation Planning and Control Approaches for Variable Friction Fingers.
- · Haptic Object Parameter Estimation during Within-Hand-Manipulation with a Simple Robot Gripper. (IEEE Haptics Symposium 2020)

### Coursework

Advanced Robot Navigation

Motion Planning

**Human Robot Interaction** 

**Robot Dynamics** 

**Robot Controls** 

Introduction to AI